Guide to the Charles Hamm Recordings, 1857-1999 HAMM.2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings on LP, 1
  - Country, 1900-1987; II.
    - Bill Monroe's Greatest Hits, 1973 (Record HAMM CON 0021)
      This album includes Molly and Tenbrooks (2:19) - In the Pines (3:08) - New Mule Skinner Blues (2:27) - Uncle Pen (2:42) - Cheyenne (2:47) - Footprints in the Snow (2:37) - Y'All Come (2:14) - Gotta Travel on (2:32) - Danny Boy (2:35) - Roanoke (2:36) - Four Walls (2:20).
    - Willie Nelson: Always on my Mind, 1982 (Record HAMM CON 0022)
      This album includes Do right woman, do right man (2:55) -- Always on my mind (3:32) -- A whiter shade of pale (4:01) -- Let it be me (3:20) -- Staring each other down (2:15) -- Bridge over troubled water (4:37) -- Old Fords and a natural stone (2:29) -- Permanently lonely (2:39) -- Last thing I needed first thing this morning (4:12) -- The party's over (2:50).
    - Willie Nelson: Lone Star, 1982 (Record HAMM CON 1982)
      This album includes Touch me -- Hello walls -- Funny how time slips away -- Crazy -- Night life -- Bloody Mary morning -- Yesterday's wine -- Bubbles in my beer -- Whiskey river -- It's not supposed to be that way -- Blue eyes crying in the rain -- Remember me -- Healing hands of time -- If you've got the money, I've got the time -- I love you a thousand ways -- Stardust -- Georgia on my mind -- Blue skies -- Faded love -- My heroes have always been cowboys.
    - Willie Nelson: Stardust, 1978 (Record HAMM CON 0024)
      This album includes Stardust (3:50) - Georgia on my mind (4:19) - Blue skies (3:32) - All of me (3:52) - Unchained melody (3:48) - September song (4:32) - On the sunny side of the street (2:35) - Moonlight in Vermont (3:23) - Don't get around much anymore (2:30) - Someone to watch over me (4:01).
    - Dolly Parton, Linda Rondstat, Emmylou Harris: Trio, 1987 (Record HAMM CON 0025)
      This album includes The pain of loving you (2:32) -- Making plans (3:36) -- To know him is to love him (3:48) -- Hobo's meditation (3:17) -- Wildflowers (3:33) -- Telling me lies (4:26) -- My dear companion (2:55) -- Those memories of you (3:58) -- I've had enough (3:30) -- Rosewood casket (2:59) -- Farther along (4:10).
    - The Legend of Charlie Poole, 1968 (Record HAMM CON 0026)
      This album includes Look before you leap -- Hungry hash house -- Old & only in the way -- Write a letter to my mother -- Goodbye booze -- My wife went away & left me -- Goodbye Liza Jane -- Leaving dear old Ireland -- Budded roses -- The highwayman -- Goodbye Mary dear -- Milwaukee blues.
    - Bonnie Raitt: Sweet Forgiveness, 1977 (Record HAMM CON 0027)
      This album includes About to make me leave home (4:11) -- Runaway (3:53) -- Two lives (3:47) -- Louise (2:43) -- Gamblin' man (3:25) -- Sweet forgiveness (4:07) -- My opening farewell (5:17) -- Three time loser (3:15) -- Takin' my time (3:34) -- Home (3:25).
    - Jim Reeves: Moonlight and Roses, 1964 (Record HAMM CON 0028)
      This album includes Moonlight and roses (Bring mem'ries of you / Black-Moret (2:24) -- Mexicali rose / Tenney-Stone (2:26) -- Carolina moon / Benny Davis-Joe Burke (2:28) -- Rosa Rio / Cindy Walker (2:53) -- Oh what it seemed to be / Carle-Weiss-Benjamin (2:52) -- What's in it for me / Cindy Walker (2:26) -- Roses / Tim Spencer-Glenn Spencer (2:28) -- One dozen roses / Jurgens ... [et al.] (1:50) -- Moon river / Mancini-Mercer (2:27) -- There's a new moon over my shoulder / Davis-Whelan-Blastic (2:37) -- It's only a paper moon / Arlen-Rose-Harburg (2:21) -- When I lost you / Irving Berlin (2:29).
    - The Best of the Legendary Jimmie Rodgers, 1965 (Record HAMM CON 0029)
      This album includes Mule Skinner Blues (Blue Yodel No. 8) (BMI 2:55); Away Out on the Mountain (BMI 3:07); Blue Yodle No. 1 (T for Texas) (BMI 3:20); Roll Along Kentucky Moon (ASCAP 2:56); The Mystery of Number Five (BMI 3:00); Why Should I Be Lonely? (BMI 3: 08); Moonlight and Skies (BMI 2:57); Any Old Time (BMI 2:47); Mother, Queen of My Heart (BMI 3:21); Why Did You Give Me Your Love? (BMI 2:38); Daddy and Home (ASCAP 2:53).
    - Kenny Rogers: Love is What We Make it, 1985 (Record HAMM CON 0030)
      This album includes Love is what we make it - Twentieth century fool - Still hold on - Tie me to your heart again - Maybe in the end - It turns me inside out - It happened in the best of dreams - A stranger in my place - Starting today, starting over - Born to love me.
    - Kenny Rogers: Ten Years of Gold, 1977 (Record HAMM CON 0031)
      This album includes Ruby don't take your love to town -- Reuben James -- But you know I love you -- Something's burning -- Just dropped in -- Lucille -- Daytime friends -- While the feeling's good -- Love lifted me -- Today I started loving you again.
    - Jean Shepard: "Many Happy Hangovers", 1966 (Record HAMM CON 0032)
      This album includes Many Happy Hangovers to You (2:27); Look what I've Got (2:09); Our Past is in My Way (2:44); How in the World (2:22); Your Name's Become A Household Word (2:47); I Forgot to Care (1:55); Wherever You Are (2:05); dirt Under His Feet (2:14); One Minutes (2:16); Day to Day (Tear to Tear) (2:15); You'd Still Find a Way to Cheat on Me (2:21); Wave Goodbye to Me (2:07).
    - Ricky Skaggs: Lonesome River, 1983 (Record HAMM CON 0033)
      This album includes We'll be sweethearts in Heaven -- Our last goodbye -- It's never too late -- White dove -- Too late to cry -- Lonesome river -- Loving you too well -- I love no one but you -- Little glass of wine -- I long to see the old folks.
    - Carl Smith's Greatest Hits, 1962 (Record HAMM CON 0034)
      This album includes Hey Joe! (B. Bryant) - There she goes (E. Miller-Haddock) - Old Lonesome times (S. James-Pitts) - Are you teasing me (I. Louvin-C. Louvin) - I feel like cryin' (W. Fairburn) - Doorstep to heaven (L. Payne) - Let old mother nature have her way (L. Southerland-L.Clark) - The little girl in my home town (C. Smith) - If you saw her through my eyes (You'd see her differently) (D. Dill-C. Smith) - You're free to go (D. Roberton-L. Herscher) - Gettin' even (E. Hamilton-W. P. Walker) - I overlooked an orchid (While searching for a rose) (Story-C. Smith-S. Lyn).
    - The Carl Smith Touch, 1960 (Record HAMM CON 0035)
      This album includes I'm not in her plans anymore /M. Tillis - I could never hurt you like this /W. Walker - Cut across shortly /M. wilkin, w. walker - Empty hours /W. Walker - I'd go through it all again /W. wilkins, w. Walker - The little white house /W. walker - Here we are again /W. walker - Why did you come my way /M. Wilkins, M. Rhodes - I won't turn the other check again /w. walker - Heart of a fool /W. Nelson, H. Craig - Past /w. Walker.
    - The Fabulous Sammi Smith (Record HAMM CON 0036)
      This album includes Don't Blow no Smoke on Me (2:03); When Michael Calls (2:20); This Room for Rent (2:54); Have I stayed Away too Long (3:22); Tony (3:02); I'm in for stormy weather (2:27); That's the Price I Pay for Loving You (2:14); Here's to Forever (2:50); Willie (3:02).
    - Stars of the Grand Ole Opry, 1926-1974 (Record HAMM CON 0037)
      This album includes Railroadin' and Gamblin'; San Antonio Rose; Orange Blossom Special; Jealous Hearted Me; Anytime; Father's Table Grace;I'm My Own Grandpa; Yakety Axe; I don't Hurt anymore;I'm Thinking Tonight of My Blue eyes; Down Yonder; Satisfied; Ashes of Love; Old Blue; How Far Is Heaven; Four Walls; Carroll County Accident; I Can't Stop Loving You; Trouble in the Amen Corner; The End of the world; early Morning Rain; send Me the Pillow You Dream On; Young Love; Morning; The Three Bells; Country Girl; Four Strong winds; Ribbon of Darkness; Mule skinner Blues; Just a Little After Heartaches.
    - The Blue Sky Boys: "The Sunny Side of Life", 1973 (Record HAMM CON 0038)
      This album includes Alabama - Sweet Allallee - In the Hills of Roane County - Are tou from Dixie - S-A-V-E-D- - Don't say goodbye if you love me - Down on the banks of the Ohio - Turn your radio on - Kentucky - Sunny side of life - pictures from life's other side - Katie dear - Lightning express - Fair-Eyed Ellen - Asleep in the briny deep - Dust on the Bible.
    - Conway Twitty: 20 Certified No. 1 Hits, 1978 (Record HAMM CON 0039)
      This album includes I've Already Loved You in My Mind; Linda On My Mind; I'm Not Through Loving You Yet; I See the Want to in Your Eyes; It's Only Make Believe; Play Guitar Play; Don't Cry Joni; Fifteen Years Ago; To See My Angel Cry; I'll Try; Hello Darlin'; The Games Daddies Play; I Can't See Me Without You; Touch The Hand; Baby's Gone; You've Never Been This Far Before; After All the Good is Gone; I Can't Believe she Gives it All to Me; (Lost Her Love) On Our Last Date; She Needs Someone to Hold Her (when She Cries).
    - Western Swing, 1966 (Record HAMM CON 0040)
      This album includes Barn dance rag - Never no more blues - Spanish Fandango - The eyes of Texas - Under the double eagle - Never no more hard time blues - Knocky knocky - Little girls go and ask your mama - Swing blues no. 1 - Steel guitar rag - Where you been so long, Corrine - Brownie stomp - You've got to Hi De Hi - French two step = Rubber dolly - Steel guitar stomp.
    - Slim Whitman: All My Best, 1979 (Record HAMM CON 0041)
      This album includes Indian love call -- Ramblin' rose -- My happines -- Room full of roses -- Blue eyes cryin' in the rain -- When my blue moon turns to gold again -- Have I told you lately that I love you -- There goes my everything -- My heart cries for you -- Let me call you sweetheart -- Rose Marie -- Vaya con dios -- Roses are red -- Somewhere my love -- I love you because -- Una paloma blance -- I can't stop loving you -- Sail along silvery moon -- You belong to my heart -- Red river valley.
    - 24 of Hank Williams' Greatest Hits, 1970 (Record HAMM CON 0042)
      This album includes Your cheatin' heart - Move it on over - I'm so lonesome I could cry - Honky Tonk blues - My heart would know - Kaw-liga - Cold, cold heart - Lovesick blues - Ramblin' man - Honky Tonkin - There'll be no teardrops tonight - Mind your own business - Jambalaya (On the Bayou) - Wedding bells - Hey, Good lookin' - Window shoping - Settin' the woods on fire - I can't help it (If I'm still in love with you) - Half as much - Why don't you love me - You win again - May you never be alone - Baby, we're really in love - Take these chains from my heart.
    - Will the Circle Be Unbroken (various artists), 1972 (Record HAMM CON 0043)
      This album includes Various content.
  - Classical, 1962-1987; I.
    This series includes classical music albums. There are 42 albums that showcase both American and European preformances of great classical musical pieces by world famous composers.
    - The Dartmouth Digital Sythesizer, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0001)
      This album includes Georganna's farewell; Lars-Gunnar Bodin (10:19); Emergence (7:22); Tapestry I (7:32).
    - The World Music Theatre of Jon Appleton, 1974 (Record HAMM CLA 0002)
      This album includes Chef d'oeuvre; Apolliana; Sones de San Blas; Nevsehir; C. C. C. P.; Hommage to Orpheus; 'Ofa atu Tonga; Times Square times ten.
    - Street Psalms: Music for Piano by Patrick Beckham, 1984 (Record HAMM CLA 0003)
      This album includes Side (A) Three Movements: 1. The night spirit and the dawn air - 2. The fork in the road - 3. The madman runs to the east.; Side (B) Three Movements: 1. The city beats - 2. Black and blues - 3. The hawk soars
    - Leonard Bernstein Conducts Music of Our Time, 1965 (Record HAMM CLA 0004)
      This album includes Atmosphères, by G. Ligeti; Out of "Last pieces," by M. Feldman; Four improvisations by the orchestra; Improvisations for orchestra and jazz soloists, by L. Austin.
    - John Cage: Concerto for Prepared Piano and Orchestra, 1968 (Record HAMM CLA 0005)
      This album includes unknown content.
    - John Cage & Lejaren Hiller: HPSCHD, 1969 (Record HAMM CLA 0006)
      This album includes Side One: (21:00) HPSCHD; Side Two: (14:57) String Quartet No.2
    - John Cage: 25 Year Retrospective Concert, 1959 (Record HAMM CLA 0007)
      This album includes Six short inventions for seven instruments; Construction in metal; Imaginary landscape no. 1; A recording of constant and variable frequency records, cymbal and piano; The wonderful widow of eighteen springs; Text adapted from Finnegans wake; She is asleep; Quartet for twelve tom toms; Duo; Sonatas and interludes; Music for carillon; Williams mix; Concerto for piano and orchestra.
    - John Cage and David Tudor: Variations IV, Volume II, 1968-1978 (Record HAMM CLA 0008)
      This album includes 1. Introduction - 2. Part I (15:30) - Part II (14:30).
    - George Crumb: Ancient Voices of children, 1971 (Record HAMM CLA 0009)
      This album includes I. El niño busca su voz - Dances of the ancient earth - II. Me he perdido muchas veces por el mar - III> De dònde vienes, amor, mi niño? - IV> Todas las tardes en Granada, todas las tardes se muere un niño - Ghost dance - V. Se ha llenado de luces mi corazón de seda.
    - The Wind Demon and Other Mid-nineteenth Century Piano Music, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0010)
      This album includes The Andes: Marche di bravoura / G.W. Warren; Dream land, op. 59 / G.F. Bristow; United States grand waltz, op. 43 / C. Grobe; A pastoral novellette / W. Mason; In memoriam L. M. G. / R. Hoffman; Dixiana / Hoffman; The wind demon: Rhapsodie caracteristique, op. 11 / C.J. Hopkins; Laurel waltz, (from the Elssler dances) / A.P. Heinrich; Romance / L.M. Gottschalk; Adieu / W.H. Fry; Grande polka de concert [op. 1] / H.N. Bartlett; Silver spring, op. 6 / Mason.
    - Peter Maxwell Davies: Dark Angels, 1977 (Record HAMM CLA 0011)
      This album includes The drowning brothers; Dark angels (guitar solo); Dead fires.
    - Jan Fryderyk Dobrowolski: The Art of Improvisation, 1970-1979 (Record HAMM CLA 0012)
      This album includes 1. Acropolis: Propylea (Temple of Nike Apteros)-Erechtheion (Old Temple of Ante)-Parthenon (Foundation of Parthenon Commenced by Cimon) - 2. Peristyles - 3. Tepidarium - 4. Laconicum
    - Charles Dodge: Earth's Magnetic Field, 1970 (Record HAMM CLA 0013)
      This album includes Earth's Magnetic Field: Realizations in computer electronic sound.
    - John Duke: Seventeen Songs, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0014)
      This album includes In the fields (Mew); The end of the world (MacLeish); Be still as you are beautiful (MacDonogh); XXth century (Hillyer); The song of wandering Aengus (Yeats); Brown penny (Yeats); Calvary (Robinson); Spring thunder (Van Doren); One red rose (Van Doren); Three Gothic ballads (Heath--Subbs): The old king. The mad knight's song. The coward's lament; Loveliest of trees (Housman); When I was one and twenty (Housman); When, in disgrace with fortune (Shakespeare); The white dress (Wolfe); I ride the great black horses (Nathan).
    - Kenneth Gaburo: Music for Voices, Instruments & electronic instruments, 1968 (Record HAMM CLA 0015)
      This album includes Antiphony III (Pearl-white moments); Exit music I: The wasting of Lucrecetzia; Antiphony IV (Poised); Exit music II: Fat Millie's lament.
    - Gershwin: Catfish Row, An American in Paris, 1987 (Record HAMM CLA 0016)
      This album includes Gershwin: 1-5. Catfish Row - 6. Lullaby - Gershwin: 1. Cuban Overture - 2. An American In Paris.
    - Gershwin: Concerto in F, Cuban Overture, 1962 (Record HAMM CLA 0017)
      This album includes Concerto in F for piano and orchestra: I. Allegro; II. Adagio: Andante con moto poco accelerando III. Allegro agitato - "I got rhythm" variations for piano and orchestra; Cuban overture.
    - Gershwin Plays Gershwin: Rhapsody in Blue, An American in Paris, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0018)
      This album includes Rapsody in Blue (9:06) - An American in Paris (15:44) - Three Preludes (4:56) - Oh Kay!: Do-Do-Do (3:02)--May be (3:12)--Someone to watch over me (3:09)--Clap yo' hands (2:44) - Tip-Toes: Looking for a boy (2:38)--Sweet and low down (2:40)--That certain feeling (2:22)--When do we dance? (2:34).
    - Malcolm Goldstein: Soundings for Solo Violin, 1979-1980 (Record HAMM CLA 0019)
    - Malcolm Goldstein: The Seasons: Vermont, 1983 (Record HAMM CLA 0020)
      This album includes Summer -- Autumn -- Winter -- Spring.
    - Charles Ives: Piano Sonata #1 (Noël Lee), 1967 (Record HAMM CLA 0021)
      This album includes I. Adagio con moto-Allegro risoluto-Adagio cantabile (7:58) - II. Allegro moderato-Chorus: Andante-In the Inn: Allegro-Chorus: Con moto (meno mosso) and evenly (6:52) - III. Largo-Più mosso-Allegro-Largo, come prima (6:52) - IV. [No tempo indicated; afastish ragtime]-Allegro-Presto-Slow (5:48) - V. Andante maestoso-Più moso-Adagio cantabile-Allegro-Andante (ma con brio) or slow allegro-agitando, accel. al fine (13:25).
    - Charles Ives: Piano Sonata #2 (Gilbert Kalish), 1976-1977 (Record HAMM CLA 0022)
      This album includes Emerson (17:44)--Hawthorne (12:28)--Alcotts (6:03)--Thoreau (12:40).
    - Edwin London: Choral Music on Old Testament Tests, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0023)
      This album includes Day of desolation (Mixed chorus and bells)--Better is, (Women's voices a cappella--Sacred hair (Mixed chorus, amplified combs & organ)--Dream thing on biblical episodes (women's voices a cappella).
    - Salvatore Martirano: L's GA, 1970 (Record HAMM CLA 0024)
      This album includes L's GA for Gassed-Masked Politico, Helium Bomb, and two Channel Tape (24:20) - Ballad (11:20) - Octet (6:52).
    - Don't Give the Name a Bad Place: Types & Stereotypes in American Musical Theater 1870-1900, 1978 (Record HAMM CLA 0025)
      This album includes The babies on our block -- Maggie Murphy's home -- John Riley's always dry -- Paddy Duffy's cart -- Hang the Mulligan banner up -- Stay in your own backyard -- De golden wedding -- My gal is a high born lady -- Darktown is out tonight -- Tell 'em I'll be there -- The German 5th -- Cat song or Can any one tell vere dot cat is gone? -- Rip Van Winkle was a lucky man -- Don't give de name a bad blace.
    - Parnassus: Works by Wolpe, Davidovsky, 1980 (Record HAMM CLA 0026)
      This album includes Stefan Wolpe: Chamber piece no. 2 (3:44) - Mario Davidovsky: Pennplay (10:30) - David Olan: Octet (10:15) - Charles Wuorinen: The winds (14:53) - Erik Lundborg: Soundsoup (10:51).
    - Morgan Powell: Music for Brass, 1970-1979 (Record HAMM CLA 0027)
      This album includes Music for brass and percussion--Old man--Inacabado--Midnight realities--Loneliness--Darkness II.
    - Steve Reich: Drumming, 1971 (Record HAMM CLA 0028)
      This album includes Eight small tuned drums, Three marimbas, Three glockenspiels, Male and Female voices, Whistling and Piccolo.
    - Steve Reich: Four Organs/Phase Patterns, 1971 (Record HAMM CLA 0029)
    - Frederic Rzewski/John Harbison, 1979 (Record HAMM CLA 0030)
      This album includes Song and dance (22:44) - The flower-fed buffaloes-- 1. The flower-fed buffaloes - II. Enrich my resignation - III. Depths - IV. Above pate valley - V. The Amaranth (20:04).
    - Peter Schickele: Pentangle, Five Songs for French Horn, 1980 (Record HAMM CLA 0031)
      This album includes Pentagle, Five songs for French horn and orchestra / Peter Schickele (25:36) - Elegy for orchestra / Francis Thorne (15:35) - Vigil / Joyge Mekeel (11:33).
    - Schwanter/Copland Lincoln Portrait and David Effron, 1983 (Record HAMM CLA 0032)
      This album includes New Morning for the world (27:10) ("…Daybreak of Freedom…") - An Eastman Overture /George Walker (8:04) - Lincoln Portrait /Aaron Copland (15:33).
    - Cornet Favorites by Clarke, Arban, 1974 (Record HAMM CLA 0033)
      This album includes Clarke, H. L. From the shores of the mighty Pacific: (Rondo caprice). Sounds from the Hudson: (Valse brillante) -- Simon, F. Willow echoes -- Arban, J. B. Fantaisie and variations on The carnival of Venice -- Thomson, V. At the beach -- Clarke, H. L. The débutanté: (caprice brillante) -- Höhne, C. Slavische Fantasie -- Clarke, H. L. The bride of the waves: (Polka brillante).
    - Ellsworth Snyder Plays New Piano Music, 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0034)
      This album includes Six moments (8:21) / Bert Levy--Piano sonata #2 (7:33) / David Ahlstrom--Something else for Ellsworth Snyder(3:45) / Charles Hamm--Treatise (Two Realizations) 1.(0.23)2.(19.40) / Cornelius Cardew.
    - Sousa Spectacular, 1982 (Record HAMM CLA 0035)
      This album includes Semper fidelis -- The high school cadets -- The Washington Post -- Jack Tar -- The loyal legion -- Anchor and star -- The stars and stripes forever -- El capitan -- Liberty bell -- Comrades of the legion -- The Corcoran cadets -- King Cotton -- Hail to the spirit of liberty -- The thunderer.
    - Morton Subotnick: The Wild Bull, 1968 (Record HAMM CLA 0036)
    - New American Music for Chamber Ensemble, 1978 (Record HAMM CLA 0037)
      This album includes Heiss, J. Songs of nature.--Shifrin, S. In eius memoriam.--Lansky, P. Crossworks.
    - Electronic Music from the University of Illinois, 1967 (Record HAMM CLA 0038)
      This album includes Machine music / L.A. Hiller -- Leomon drops; For Harry / K. Gaburo -- Canto / C. Hamm -- Futility / H. Brün -- Underworld / S. Martirano.
    - Computer Music from the University of Illinois, 1967 (Record HAMM CLA 0039)
      This album includes Illiac Suite for string quartet / by Lejaren Hiller & Leonard Isaacson -- Computer Cantata / by Lejaren Hiller & Robert Baker.
    - When I have Sung My Songs [The American Art Song, 1900-1940], 1976 (Record HAMM CLA 0040)
      This album includes Long ago, sweetheart mine, op. 56, no. 1 / E. MacDowell -- A maid sings light, op. 56, no. 3 / MacDowell -- The year's at the spring, op. 44, no. 1 / Mrs. H.H.A. Beach -- Love in May, op. 51, no. 1 / H.W. Parker -- The lark now leaves his watery nest, op. 47, no. 6 / H.W. Parker -- Swans, op. 44, no. 4 / A.W. Kramer -- The bitterness of love / J.P. Dunn -- Danny Deever, op. 2, no. 7 / W.J. Damrosch -- Go down, Moses / H.T. Burleigh -- Heav'n, heav'n / Burleigh -- Deep river / Burleigh -- At dawning, op. 29, no. 1 / C.W. Cadman -- By a lonely forest pathway / C.T. Griffes -- Do not go, my love / R. Hageman -- When I bring you coloured toys / J.A. Carpenter -- Light, my light / Carpenter -- Velvet shoes / R. Thompson -- When I have sung my songs / E. Charles -- Lit'l gal / J.R. Johnson -- General William Booth enters into heaven / C.E. Ives.
    - Christian Wolff: Lines for String Quartet, 1972 (Record HAMM CLA 0041)
      This album includes 1. Movemetn (7:07) - 2. Entr'acte I: Vergine bella (3:35) - 3. Movement II (15:19) - 1. Entr'acte II Vergine bella (4:42) - 2. Movement III (10:45).
    - Charles Wuorinen: Percussion Symphony, 1978 (Record HAMM CLA 0042)
- Irving Berlin Research, 2
  - London Research '92, 1992; 1
    - List of Irving Berlin Songs, 1
    - The Music of Irving Berlin, 1907-1914; 2
    - Notes of song listings, 3
    - Regulations for the Use of the Reading Rooms at the British Library, Humanities and Social Sciences, 4
    - David Horn, director of the Institute of Popular Music at the University of Liverpool to Charles Hamm, typed letter, signed, 1992-01-20; 5
    - Charles Hamm to Malcolm Turner, Deputy Music Librarian of the British Library, typed letter, unsigned, 1992-04-20; 6
    - Flyer detailing the temporary Relocation of Reader Admission at the British Library, 1992-10-13; 7
    - Malcolm Turner to Charles Hamm, typed letter, unsigned, 1992-10-07; 8
    - Research notes, undated, 9 pages, undated, 10
  - New York Public Library, 1992; 2
    - Research notes, undated, 1
    - Irving Berlin Discography, with Publishing Information, undated, 2
    - Schneider, Wayne and Olsen, Paula to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1992-05-21; 3
  - New York City Research, 1995-03; 3
    - Research Notes for the Robinson Loche Collection, 1995-09-02; 1